# dr. ir. Roland M. van Rijswijk-Deij

University of Twente Faculty EEMCS (room ZI-5098) Design and Analysis of Communications Systems NL-7522 NB Enschede

☐ r.m.vanrijswijk@utwente.nl 

http://wwwhome.ewi.utwente.nl/~rijswijkrm

The Netherlands in http

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rolandvanrijswijk

**EDUCATION** 

02/2014 - 06/2017

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science (cum laude)

University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands

09/1995 - 08/2001 Master of Science in Computer Science

University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands

Professional Experience

09/2008 - present SURFnet, Utrecht, The Netherlands

R&D Project Manager and Researcher

DNS, DNSSEC, Network Security, Network Measurements

11/2006 – 08/2008 InTraffic, Nieuwegein, The Netherlands

Lead Software Designer

Control Software for Railway and Public Transport Infrastructure

10/2002 - 11/2006 **AET Europe**, Arnhem, The Netherlands

Senior Software Engineer

Cryptographic Middleware and Embedded Software for Smart Cards

09/2001 - 10/2002 Royal Philips Electronics, Eindhoven, The Netherlands

Software and Test Engineer

Embedded Software for Digital Video Broadcasting and IP TV (a.o.)

01/2001 - 08/2001 Royal Philips Electronics, Eindhoven, The Netherlands

Master Thesis Work in Embedded Systems

In-Home Networks

09/2000 - 12/2000 British Telecommunications (BT) R&D, Ipswich, United Kingdom

Industrial Traineeship

Smart Cards and Hardware IPSec Implementation

ACADEMIC POSITIONS

11/2017 - present University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands

Assistant Professor (part-time)

In the Design and Analysis of Communication Systems Group, Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Maths and Computer Science

07/2017 - 10/2017 University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands

 $Guest\ Researcher$ 

02/2014 - 06/2017 University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands

Ph.D. Candidate

02/2016 - 03/2016 CAIDA, University of California at San Diego, United States

Visiting Researcher

02/2013 - 02/2014 Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

Ph.D. Candidate

## SELECTED PUBLICATIONS (FULL LIST SEE HTTPS://RIJSWIJK.GITHUB.10/)

- [1] T. Chung, R. van Rijswijk-Deij, B. Chandrasekaran, D. Choffnes, D. Levin, B.M. Maggs, A. Mislove and C. Wilson. *A Longitudinal, End-to-End View of the DNSSEC Ecosystem*. In Proceedings of the 26th USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security '17). Vancouver, BC, Canada: USENIX Association. (Acceptance Rate: 16.3%)
- [2] R. van Rijswijk-Deij, K. Hageman, A. Sperotto, and A. Pras. *The Performance Impact of Elliptic Curve Cryptography on DNSSEC Validation*. IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking, vol. 25, no. 2, 2017. (*Impact Factor 2016/2017: 3.376*)
- [3] R. van Rijswijk-Deij, M. Jonker, A. Sperotto, and A. Pras. A High-Performance, Scalable Infrastructure for Large-Scale Active DNS Measurements. IEEE Journal of Selected Areas in Communications, vol. 34, no. 7, pp. 1877–1888, 2016. (Impact Factor 2016/2017: 8.085)
- [4] R. van Rijswijk-Deij, A. Sperotto, and A. Pras. *DNSSEC and Its Potential for DDoS Attacks*. In Proceedings of ACM IMC 2014, 2014. (Acceptance Rate: 22.9%)
- [5] G. van den Broek, R. van Rijswijk-Deij, A. Sperotto, and A. Pras. DNSSEC Meets Real World: Dealing with Unreachability Caused by Fragmentation. IEEE Communications Magazine, vol. 52, no. April, pp. 154–160, 2014. (Impact Factor 2014: 4.007)

#### AWARDS

## 2017 USENIX Security Distinguished Paper Award

for the paper "A Longitudinal, End-to-End View of the DNSSEC Ecosystem" [1] presented at the  $26^{\rm th}$  USENIX Security Symposium, August 16-18, 2017, Vancouver, BC, Canada

#### IRTF Applied Networking Research Prize (ANRP)

for the paper "The Performance Impact of Elliptic Curve Cryptography on DNSSEC Validation" [2] to be presented at IETF 100 in Singapore, November 2017

#### 2015 IRTF Applied Networking Research Prize (ANRP)

for the paper "DNSSEC and Its Potential for DDoS Attacks" [4] presented at IETF 94 in Yokohama, Japan, November 2015

#### 2014 ACM SIGCOMM IMC Community Contribution Award

for the paper "DNSSEC and Its Potential for DDoS Attacks" [4] presented at ACM SIGCOMM IMC 2014, Vancouver, BC, Canada, November 2014

### MASTER STUDENTS

Boudewijn Ector (2009), Niels Monen (2011), Gijs van den Broek (2012), Sean Rijs (2014), Kaspar Hageman (2015), Romanos Dodopoulos (2015), Tho Le (2017), Olivier van der Toorn (2017)

# SHORT BIOGRAPHY

Roland van Rijswijk-Deij was born in Arnhem, The Netherlands, on March 17<sup>th</sup>, 1977. He holds an M.Sc. degree in Computer Science from the University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands (2001). Roland received a *cum laude* Ph.D. degree from the University of Twente in June 2017, for his thesis entitled "Improving DNS Security: a Measurement-Based Approach". Roland has a background in embedded systems, applied cryptography and networking. He previously worked for British Telecom (2000, traineeship), Royal Philips Electronics (2001-2002), AET Europe (2002-2006) and InTraffic (2006-2008).

Since 2008, Roland works for SURFnet, the National Research and Education Network in The Netherlands. At SURFnet, Roland is responsible for SURFnet's DNS and DNSSEC infrastructure. He also initiates and leads innovation projects in the area of Internet security and stability. Past innovation projects initiated by Roland have focused on DNS, DNSSEC, detecting and mitigating DDoS attacks, IPv6 and many other topics. Roland regularly presents his work in international networking venues, such as TNC, Internet2 conferences, IETF meetings, ICANN meetings, RIPE meetings and NANOG.

Next to his work at SURFnet, Roland has a part-time position as assistant professor computer network security in the Design and Analysis of Communication Systems group at the University of Twente.